Guide to the Noman M. Cole, Jr. papers, 1962-1996
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Noman M. Cole, Jr. papers
1962-1996
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Noman M. Cole (Noman Monroe ), 1933-1997
C0066
19 linear feet (39 boxes)
This collection covers his environmental work (particularly in the area of water pollution control and reclamation) in Northern Virginia and other areas in the Commonwealth. Materials include reports on the design, operation, and performance of pollution control systems; correspondence; studies; news clippings; and motion picture film. Organizations in the collection include: Virginia Department of Environmental Quality, Virginia State Water Control Board, Metropolitan Council of Governments, and Fairfax County Government.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Janet Cole in 2004.
Biographical Information
Noman M. Cole, Jr. was a leading figure in the area of environmental quality in the Northern Virginia area and elsewhere. Mr. Cole served in a variety of state and local assignments pertaining to pollution control. He was technical and policy adviser to Governors John Dalton and Linwood Holton on energy and water pollution abatement. The government of Fairfax County and civic groups received guidance from him as well. Mr. Cole also was the principal author of the 1971 Occoquan Watershed Policy, which prompted creation of a sewage authority there as well as of a world-class treatment plant.
Mr. Cole's expertise also extended to global issues. He was a nuclear engineer who was a leader in the inspection and rectification of problems involving the reactor after the Three Mile Island accident in Pennsylvania. He served on the Ukrainian international jury reviewing proposals to stabilize Chernobyl Unit No. 4 after the disaster there. Mr. Cole assisted the Russian government in defueling its nuclear-powered submarines.
Later in his life, and most importantly for the Northern Virginia region, he developed a number of plants and processes to aid in the reclamation of water from the upper Occoquan and consequentially, the lower Potomac watersheds. His engineering expertise and unmitigated success in this area led grateful water treatment officials to name a plant in Lorton, Virginia in his name.
Scope and Content
This collection covers his environmental work (particularly in the area of water pollution control and reclamation) in Northen Virginia and other areas in the Commonwealth. Materials include reports on the design, operation, and performance of pollution control systems; correspondence; studies; news clippings; and motion picture film. Organizations in the collection include: Virginia Department of Environmental Quality, Virginia State Water Control Board, Metropolitan Council of Governments, and Fairfax County Government.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by subject.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the Carol D. Litchfield Microbiology collection.
Index Terms
Persons:
Cole, Noman M. (Noman Monroe ), 1933-1997
Corporate Names:
Virginia. Dept. of Environmental Quality.; Virginia. State Water Control Board.
Geographical Names:
Fairfax County (Va.)--Politics and government.
Subjects:
Environmental policy--Virginia.
Contents List
- Noman Cole
  - Pohick Plant Expansion 18 to 36 MGD (1972 - 73) Lower Potomac Plant. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Pohick Plant Expansion 18 to 36 MGD (1972 - 73) Lower Potomac Plant. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Pohick Plant Expansion 18 to 36 MGD (1972 - 73) Lower Potomac Plant. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Court Cases. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter from James E. Ryan, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - HYDRILLA. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lower Potomac Plant Operations. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pohick Plant - Feasibility Report. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pohick Plant Design Corrections Property of N. Cole. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pohick Plant Bypass Line, etc. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Mason Neck/Lower Potomac Plant Proposed Expansion - 1988. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Re: Lower Potomac Plant Carbon Columns - 1979. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Pohick Plant Newsclips 1970. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Educational Materials on Sewage Treatment. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Educational Materials on Sewage Treatment. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Chesapeake Bay Technical Reports. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Washington Area Treatment Plant Data Reports 1990 - 1992. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Roanoke Matters. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Mattawomen Sewage Plant. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Alexandria Plant 1970 - 1974. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Draft for Public Review Comment. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - WSSC and Blue Plans Agreement June 1974. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - WSSC and Blue Plans Agreement June 1974. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Embayment Standards 1994 - 1996 [ I ]. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Embayment Standards 1994 - 1996 [ II ]. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Embayment Standards 1994 - 1996 [ III ]. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1992 to 1994 Embayment Standards Viewgraphs. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Embayment Standards Letters, etc. 1995 - 1996. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - HRSD Newsclips. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - New Treatment Process [ I ]. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - New Treatment Process [ II ]. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Embayment Standards Letters 1994. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Studies - NHO3 - NO3; Phosphorus; Viruses, etc [ II ]. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Studies - NHO3 - NO3; Phosphorus; Viruses, etc [ I ]. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Embayment Standards 1995. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - backup V.G (P/NH4). (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - C - (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - B - SS. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - A - SS. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Cole (Dizevegn Historian). (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Summary of Issues Concerning Viruses in Sewage plant Effluent and the Role of Suspended Solids i Controlling Viruses. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Sequence of Events Regarding the Matter of Potomac Embayment Standards. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Shenandoah River Pumpover Water Supply Proposal 1977 for Governor John Dalton [ I ]. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Shenandoah River Pumpover Water Supply Proposal 1977 for Governor John Dalton [ II ]. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Report of Committee Assigned to Study the Means of Encouraging Industrial Development in Fairfax County. October 1976. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Energy Action Program for Virginia - 1977 for Lt. Gov. John N. Dalton [ I ]. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Energy Action Program for Virginia - 1977 for Lt. Gov. John N. Dalton [ II ]. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax County Goals Advisory Commission December in 1987 [ I ]. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Fairfax County Goals Advisory Commission December in 1987 [ II ]. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Commission on Fiscal and Spending Priorities 1992. Fairfax County [ I ]. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Commission on Fiscal and Spending Priorities 1992. Fairfax County [ II ]. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Commission on Fiscal and Spending Priorities 1992. Fairfax County [ III ]. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Dominion Semi - Conductor - Sodium Issue. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Dominion Semi - Conductor - Sodium Issue. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Dominion Semi - Conductor / Sodium Concentration [ I ]. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Dominion Semi - Conductor / Sodium Concentration [ II ]. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Dominion Semi - Conductor / Sodium Concentration [ III ]. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Embayment Standards XX - 93. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Embayment Standards XX - 93. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - New Changes to Va SWCB Laws / Regs. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - County SWCB Embayment Correspondents. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - County / SWCB Study - Feb 91. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - SWCB Cancellation of Embayment. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Overall Summary of plant Performance. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Resolution of Embayment. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - back Ground VGI Sewage Plants. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Special - Extra. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Orig Task Force VG Feb 1991. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - 1992 Viewgrephs. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 1993 Viewgrephs Presentation. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Embayment Standards. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Embayment Standards 1993. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Final Version 93. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Total Suspended Solids UG. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Basic Issue Embayment Standards. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - a) Potomac Enforcement Early 1970's / b) Embayment Standards. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Potomac Plants 1971 Re: Embayment Standards. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Embayment Standards Mooney Plant - 1978. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Embayment Standards 1981. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - History Embayment Standards 1983. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - VIMS / NVPPC - Embayment Efficient Recommendation 1983 - ?? (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Gunston Cove Embayment Study 1985 Carl Cerco. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Potomac Embayments Wasteload Allocation Study 1987. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Embayment Standard Issue 1988. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Run - Off 1983. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Fairfax Resolution 1991. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Task Force Report. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Embayment Standards N. Cole Review - Nov. 1991. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Summary of Sewage Plant Performance. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Presentation Outline. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax Board Resolution. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Newsclips - 1991 Embayment Standards Issue. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Algal Bloom Rpt. and N. Cole Reaction. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 1983 Algal Bloom Rpt. Jaworski et al. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - COG Report. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Algae Panel Report. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - COG - Lowering of Standards. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Detail history - Fairfax County. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Fairfax history of Lowering Standards Gozikowski - Sep 30. 1981. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Algae - Phosphorus Studies. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Urban Runoff Project. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - The 1983 Potomac River Algae Problem. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Blue Plains - 1983. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Runoff 4 L. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Weather 3 L. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Outline Initial Findings 1 L. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - COG and F. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - N. Cole Potomac Study. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Plan Supplement Final Approved Draft Dec. 18, 1980. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 1983 - 1985 Potomac River Algae [ I ]. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 1983 - 1985 Potomac River Algae [ II ]. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - 1983 - 1985 Potomac River Algae [ III ]. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Sept. 27 Hearing - SWCB. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Definitions. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Plant Location and Capacity (% Virginia). (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Compromiser. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Extra Copies. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - County and SWCB Itrs 1983 - Potomac Prob. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Conclusions 8 Small. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Nitrification 7 Small. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Area Plants 6 Small. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Lakes and Embayment 5 Small. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Weather 3 Small. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Algae Obser 2 Small. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Outline: Initial Findings 1 Small. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - County Position on Algae. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - COG - Algae Report 1983. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Cost Data. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - COG Computer Model. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Recommended Action 8 L. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Conclusions 8 L. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Nitrify 7 L. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Metro Area - Phosphorus Comparison. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Area Performance 6 L. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - History. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Lakes and Embayment 5 L. (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - 1983 Wastewater Treatment Division Department of Public Works. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - 1980 Annual Report of Alexandria Sanitation Authority. (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Assessment of 1978 Water Quality Conditions in the Upper Potomac Estuary. (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - 1983 - Plant Data on Phosphorus. (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - 1983 - Blue Plains Operating Date. (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - 1982 - Blue Plains Data. (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - 1983 - Blue Plain Permit and Court Order. (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Lower Potomac Plant Phosphorus Discharges. (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Weather and River Flow. (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - River Flow. (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Choph A Sampling. (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - 1983 - River Data. (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Virginia State Water Control Board Involvement in the Blue Plains Sewage System Problems - 1970 - 1974 [ I ]. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Virginia State Water Control Board Involvement in the Blue Plains Sewage System Problems - 1970 - 1974 [ II ]. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Virginia State Water Control Board Involvement in the Blue Plains Sewage System Problems - 1970 - 1974 [ III ]. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Blue Plains, Sep 1970 to Dec 1971. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Blue Plains, Sep 1970 to Dec 1971. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Blue Plains Design Date and Permit [ I ]. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Blue Plains Design Date and Permit [ II ]. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Blue Plains Masters [ I ]. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Blue Plains Masters [ II ]. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Washington Area Proposal. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Blue Plains Bill. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Blue Plains Case 1973 - 1974 [ I ]. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Blue Plains Case 1973 - 1974 [ II ]. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Blue Plains Case 1973 - 1974 [ III ]. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Files on Blue Plains (1978 - 1979). (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Blue Plains Out Flows 1970 - 1972. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Current Water Quality Conditions and Investigations in the upper Potomac River Tidal System: Technical Report No. 41 May 1970. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Water Quality and Wastewater Loadings Upper Potomac Estuary During 1969 November 1969. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - The Potomac Interceptor: Symbol of Metropolitan Cooperation Sept. 1968. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Water Pollution COntrol Plant of the District of Columbia, March 1967. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Project C: Improvements to the Sewerage System of the Nation's Capital April 1st 1968. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Wolman, Abel and Geyor, John C. Report on Sanitary Sewers and Wastewater Disposal in the Washington Metropolitan Region, 1962. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Blue Plains, January 1972, and other Letters, etc. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Committee on Water Quality Criteria. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - An Ecological Evaluation of the Heated Discharge from the Possem Point Power Station on Photoplankton Blooms in the Potomac River Estuary. February 11, 1972. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - A Report of Progress and Conclusions january 1973. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Blue Plains 1995 - 1996 Nitrogen Removal. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Blue Plains and Washington Area Wastewater Treatment Plants Take Leadership Role in Cleaning up the Potomac River. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Blue Plains Intermunicipal Agreement of 1985. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Blue Plains Case 1983 - 1984. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Potomac Estuary Water Quality Sensitivity Analysis. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - DC Sludge 1983. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Blue Plains 1974. Agreements for Sept. 1973 Lawsuit. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - CDM, Blue Plains Study. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Virginia State Water Control Board Involvement in the Blue Plains Sewage Problems 1970 - 1974 [ I ]. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Virginia State Water Control Board Involvement in the Blue Plains Sewage Problems 1970 - 1974 [ II ]. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Virginia State Water Control Board Involvement in the Blue Plains Sewage Problems 1970 - 1974 [ III ]. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Chapter 10, Study Area I Water Quality Management Plan for Northern Virginia. Draft, April 1974. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Phase I, Water Quality Management Plan for Northern Virginia. Drafts, October 1973. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Study Area I Wastewater Treatment Study Phase I Draft, November 1973. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Northern Fairfax / Dulles / Leesburg / Loudoun County 1973 - 1974 [ I ]. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Northern Fairfax / Dulles / Leesburg / Loudoun County 1973 - 1974 [ II ]. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Northern Fairfax / Dulles / Leesburg / Loudoun County 1973 - 1974 [ III ]. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Northern Fairfax / Dulles / Leesburg / Loudoun County 1973 - 1974 [ IV ]. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Files on Study Area I. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Summary Report to the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors Concerning the Sewer Situation in the Northern Portion of Fairfax County Feb. 12, 1976. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Study Area I Wastewater Treatment Study Phase 2. Draft, April 1974. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Reston Preliminary Wastewater Management Study. Feb 1974. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Moratorium - Fairfax County 1970 - 1971. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax County Sewer Overload Problem 1970. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Study Area I. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Fairfax County's Long and Short Range Sewage Programs 1970 [ I ]. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Fairfax County's Long and Short Range Sewage Programs 1970 [ II ]. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax County's Sewage Problems of 1970 and 1971 [ I ]. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax County's Sewage Problems of 1970 and 1971 [ II ]. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - 1976 Sewer Committee. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Fairfax Case Camelot Builders V. Board of Supervisors 1973 [ I ]. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Fairfax Case Camelot Builders V. Board of Supervisors 1973 [ II ]. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax Case Camelot Builders V. Board of Supervisors 1973 [ III ]. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - "F" Street Pumping Station and Wastage Plant 1974 [ I ]. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - "F" Street Pumping Station and Nestage Plant 1974 [ II ]. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Occoquan Basin Study March 1982. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - FCWA (Re: OBS) 1981. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Settlement of the Occoquan Basin Case January 1985. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Review of the Fairfax County Planning Staff's Occoquan Basin Study. Oct 17, 1983. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Report "Fun and Games wit Sewers in Fairfax County" 1983. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Occoquan, Letters 1970 and 1971 1 of 2. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Occoquan, Letters 1970 and 1971 2 of 2. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Occoquan, Report and Letters 1 of 2. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Occoquan, Report and Letters 2 of 2. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Draft Tahoe East for the Occoquan December 1970. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Tahoe East for the Occoquen January 15, 1971. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Lake Tahoe Plant 1 of 2. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Lake Tahoe Plant 2 of 2. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax - Interim Occoquan Plan and Fairfax cost and financial Data 1970 - 1972. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax - Interim Occoquan Plan and Fairfax Cost and Financial Data - 1971 and 1972. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - P.W. County Issue, 1972. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Files and Letters - Town of Manassas Interim Occoquan Plan 1971 - 1973. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Manassas Park. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Loudoun County. The Occoquan Basin 1971 - 72. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Fauquier County - Occoquan. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Summary Report - Occoquan Virus Issue (Master Draft) April 24, 1971. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Summary Report - Occoquan Virus Issue (Revised) May 15, 1971. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Advanced Wastewater Treatment as Practiced at south Tahoe. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Water Quality Office. August 1971. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Wastewater Treatment at lake Tahoe. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Eutrophication of Surface waters - Indian Creek Reservoir. First Progress Report May 1970. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - New Concepts in Water Purification Van Nostrand Reinhold Environmental Engineering Series 1974. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Summary of Facility Plan for South Tahoe Public Utility District Wastewater Treatment System. May 1978. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - A Cost Apportionment Study for the Occoquan Watershed. August 17, 1970. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Phosphorus Removal with Alum February 22, 1971. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Wastewater Reuse Early 1970's. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Occoquan - UOSA Newsclips - 1970 - 1980 1 of 2. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Occoquan - UOSA Newsclips - 1970 - 1980 2 of 2. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Reports and Letters - USOA - Volume II. Mid 1970 to 1980 1 of 3. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Reports and Letters - USOA - Volume II. Mid 1970 to 1980 2 of 3. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Reports and Letters - USOA - Volume II. Mid 1970 to 1980 3 of 3. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Articles and Reports - Source of Pollution in the Occoquan Reservoir. October 1978. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Movie on the Lake Tahoe Treatment Plant "Wastewater" - Reject or Resource?. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - UOSA/GMSD Evaluation Based on FY 80 Data. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Occoquan Case - Crouch - Vol I - 1973 1 of 4. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Occoquan Case - Crouch - Vol I - 1973 2 of 4. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Occoquan Case - Crouch - Vol I - 1973 3 of 4. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Occoquan Case - Crouch - Vol I - 1973 4 of 4. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Occoquan Case - Crouch - Vol I 1973 4 of 4. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Occoquan Case - Crouch -m Vol - II - Calculations and Projects. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - VG - Small Jurisdiction Account. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - VG - Large Jurisdiction Account. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - UOSA Study 1984. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Flow Capacities. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - SWCB - O.P. 1971. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - UOSA Letter. May 5, 1972. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - O.P - SWCB March, 1981. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - UOSA Letter June 26, 1972. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Nitrogen. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Plant Expansion. (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - SWCB Actions. (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Occoquan Policy. (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Water Reuse - Viruses. (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Miscellanies Files Related to UOSA 1 of 4. (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Files Related to UOSA 2 of 4. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Files Related to UOSA 3 of 4. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Files Related to UOSA 4 of 4. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - An Outline Plan for Wastewater Management in the Occoquan Watershed. April 1970. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Interm Report to the Virginia Water Control Board upon a Comprehensive Pollution Abatement Program for the Occoquan Watershed March 18, 1970. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - 1969 Occoquan Reservoir Study April 1970. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Report to the Virginia State Water Control Board on Virus Removal by Wastewater and Water Treatment Process. May 6, 1971. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Bull Run Sewage Plan. March 1971. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Development of the Occoquan Policy and UOSA Chronology. Noman M. Cole, Jr. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Background information on the Issue of Urban Runoff and incremental increase in Sewer Capacity. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia Waterworks Regulations. June, 1977. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Summary Report Concerning EPA's "Operable unit" Requirement And Its Effects on the Capital Cost of the UOSA Project. October 19, 1978. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Reverification of Occoquan Basin Computer Model for Post - AWT Conditions. November 1982. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Settlement with Prince William County, Manassas Park, City of Manassas over Use of UOSA, by SWCB. December 1984. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Fun and Games with Sewers in Fairfax County. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - UOSA Plant Evaluation Study. April 1984. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Nitrogen (UOSA). (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - UOSA Sludge. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Work Product. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - UOSA and GMSD Cost Issues. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - GMSD Inf. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - UOSA - Monthly Report. (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Occoquan Watershed Monitoring Laboratory. (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Burp. (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - OWML - Letter. (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Impact of Run-off on Chlorophyll "A" Levels in Occoquan Reservoir per OBS. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Toxic Chamical Control. (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Carbon Columns - UOSA. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - UOSA / DAM. (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Slides - Occoquan Reservoir, 1969. (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Upper Occoquan Sewage Authority Solid Management Report. January 1976. (Box 36, Folder 6)